Welcome. In the last lecture, we successfully set up a control rig inside of our NMP, and
欢迎。在上一讲中，我们成功地在NMP中设置了一个控制装置，并且
using the sphere trace and draw transform functions it provides, now we have a new way
使用它提供的球体追踪和绘图变换功能，现在我们有了一种新的方法
to detect the surface in front of us when we are climbing.
来检测我们面前的表面。
But the thing is, how can we actually use this to fix our hands and feet placement?
但问题是，我们如何才能真正利用这个来固定我们的手和脚的位置？
To do that, let's be clear about what we want here. So we want to erase this offset between
要做到这一点，让我们清楚地知道我们在这里想要什么。所以我们要消除手和表面之间的偏移
the hands and the surface when we are climbing. In other words, we need to know how much we
当我们攀爬时，手和表面之间的偏移。换句话说，我们需要知道我们应该在多大程度上
should move our hands towards the surface, and that's something the sphere trace can
换句话说，我们需要知道我们的手应该向表面移动多少，而这一点球体追踪可以
tell us.
告诉我们。
So by using sphere traces here, there are two pieces of information. So we already know
所以通过在这里使用球体追踪，有两个信息。所以我们已经知道
the head location and we know the location of our hand bone. And by doing a simple calculation
头部的位置，我们知道手骨的位置。通过做一个简单的计算
here, we can know the exact distance that we need to move our hands towards the surface.
我们就可以知道我们的手需要向表面移动的确切距离。
So let's look at how we can set this up. Go back to my viewport, I'm going to go back
所以让我们来看看我们如何设置这个。回到我的视口，我将回到
to my control rig. Since this is something that we'll use over and over again later,
到我的控制设备。因为这是我们以后要反复使用的东西、
I like to create a function to handle it. So I'm going to go to my blueprint tab and
我喜欢创建一个函数来处理它。所以我将进入我的蓝图标签，然后点击这个按钮。
I'm going to click this button here to create a function. So click it. Then I'm going to
我将点击这个按钮来创建一个函数。所以点击它。然后我将
rename this function to climb_ik_trace and drag out this node. So same as blueprint or
重命名这个函数为climb_ik_trace，然后拖出这个节点。所以和蓝图或
C++, we can give this function different function inputs. And the first function input that
C++，我们可以给这个函数不同的函数输入。而第一个函数输入
I like to add will be something called rig_element_key. So select this one and I'm going to change its
我想添加的第一个函数是叫做rig_element_key的东西。所以选择这个，我将把它的
name to ik_bone to trace_from. So later we can tell this function, which ik_bone is you
名字改为ik_bone到trace_from。所以以后我们可以告诉这个函数，哪个ik_bone是你的
use as a starting point to do the severe trace. All right, first thing I'm going to drag out
作为一个起点来进行严格的追踪。好的，我首先要拖出
this pane and select get_transform. Then click this dropdown for transform. I'm going to
这个窗格，选择get_transform。然后点击Transform的下拉菜单。我将会
drag out this translation pane and promote it to a local variable. So this can prevent
拖出这个翻译窗格，并将其提升为一个局部变量。所以这可以防止
us from a messy graph and the local variable is only visible to the function. All right,
乱的图形，而且这个局部变量只对函数可见。好的、
I'm going to click compile in here and this is the local variable that I just created.
我将在这里点击编译，这是我刚刚创建的局部变量。
I'm going to rename it to input_ik_bone_translation and connect this pane to here. And the next
我将把它重命名为input_ik_bone_translation，并把这个窗格连接到这里。而接下来
thing I'm going to drag out this pane and type in sequence. And we can add pane here
我将拖出这个窗格并输入序列。我们可以在这里添加窗格
if there are multiple things that we need to do. Again, just a cleaner way to create
如果我们有多件事情需要做的话。同样，只是用一种更简洁的方式来创建
a graph. So first thing I'm going to set up the trace_start and end for our severe trace.
一个图表。所以，首先我要为我们的严重追踪设置追踪的开始和结束。
So drag out this local variable, select get, then drag out this pane. I'm going to use a
所以拖出这个局部变量，选择获取，然后拖出这个窗格。我将使用一个
subtract node in here and give it a value of five for the y. So our trace will start
在这里使用一个减法节点，给它一个5的y值。
at five units behind the bone that we selected and move this node out a little bit. So I'd
从我们选择的骨头后面的5个单位开始，然后把这个节点移出去一点。所以我想
like to promote this to a local variable and click compile. I'm going to rename this local
想把它提升到一个局部变量，然后点击编译。我将把这个局部变量重命名为
variable to severe trace start and connect this a pane to here. Then I'm going to drag
变量重命名为严厉的跟踪开始，并将这个窗格连接到这里。然后我将把
out this ik_bone_translation again, get. This time I'm going to use add. Same as what we
再拖出这个ik_bone_translation，得到。这一次我将使用添加。和我们做的一样
did and give it a value of 15 units for the y. And promote this to a local variable. Click
给它一个15个单位的y值，并把它提升到一个局部变量。点击
compile. Rename this to severe trace end and connect this one to here. All right, this
编译。把这个重命名为严厉的跟踪端，把这个连接到这里。好了，这
is what we have so far. Now with all of these values cached, the next thing that I want
这就是我们到目前为止所拥有的。现在，有了所有这些值的缓存，我想做的下一件事是
to do, I'm going to create another function input. So I want to be able to toggle the
要做的下一件事，我将创建另一个函数输入。所以我希望能够通过简单的操作来切换
debug shape on and off by simply taking a boolean in here. So I'm going to create another function
调试形状的开关，只需在这里取一个布尔值。所以我将创建另一个函数
input, change it to boolean. Change its name to show_debug_shape and click compile. Then
输入，把它改为布尔值。把它的名字改为show_debug_shape，然后点击编译。然后
move through the end of this graph and we can directly get help with the function input
移动到这个图的末尾，我们可以直接得到函数输入的帮助。
that we created. So right mouse button click and type in get show_debug_shape. And hold
我们创建的。所以鼠标右键点击，输入get show_debug_shape。并按住
down b on my keyboard to bring out the branch node. So if this condition is true, connect
按住我的键盘上的b，带出分支节点。所以，如果这个条件是真的，把
this one to here. I'm going to use the function draw_debug_line. I'll draw a line, connect
这个节点到这里。我将使用函数draw_debug_line。我将画一条线，连接
it to here. Then drag out this severe trace start, select get it, pass it to a. Drag out
它连接到这里。然后拖出这个严重跟踪的开始，选择得到它，把它传给a。
this severe trace end, connect it to b. Change the thickness to 3 and I'm going to drag down
把厚度改成3，然后我把这个返回节点拖下来。
this return node and organize my graph a bit. So connect this b to return. Alright, I like
这个返回节点，把我的图组织一下。所以把这个b连接到返回。好了，我喜欢
to test this. So go back to my forward_solve. I'm going to delete all of these nodes and
来测试这个。所以回到我的forward_solve。我将删除所有这些节点，并且
I'm going to drag out this climb_ik trace. So connect it to here. Click this drop down
我将拖出这个climb_ik轨迹。所以把它连接到这里。点击这个下拉菜单
to select a bone. And in this drop down here I'm going to select the bone ik_foot_l and
来选择一个骨头。在这个下拉菜单中，我将选择骨骼ik_foot_l，并采取这个show_debug_shape。
take this show_debug_shape. And there it is. Our function is working. And it's time for
拿出这个show_debug_shape。这就是了。我们的函数正在工作。现在是时候进行
a challenge. So our challenge is I'd like you to create a function to do the climb_ik
一个挑战。我们的挑战是，我希望你们创建一个函数来做爬行_ik
trace. This is the function that we need to use over and over again later. And same as
追踪。这就是我们以后需要反复使用的函数。和我一样
I did, I'd like you to provide the function with necessary inputs. So things like the
我所做的，我希望你为这个函数提供必要的输入。因此，像
input bone element and the ability to toggle the debug shape on and off. And after this
输入骨元素，以及打开和关闭调试形状的能力。而在这之后
step I'd like you to also set up severe trace in your function as well. Remember, using
我希望你也能在你的函数中设置严重的跟踪。记住，在你的函数中使用
local variables in your function can help to create a cleaner graph. Alright, pause the
在你的函数中使用局部变量可以帮助创建一个更干净的图形。好了，暂停一下
video now and give this a go. I'll come back if you need help.
现在暂停视频，试试这个。如果你需要帮助，我会回来的。
Welcome back. How was that? Hopefully at this point you already have your climb_ik trace
欢迎回来。刚才怎么样？希望在这一点上，你已经准备好了你的 climb_ik 跟踪
function ready. Don't worry if you ran into any issues. Let's look at how I would do it.
函数准备好了。如果你遇到了任何问题，不要担心。让我们来看看我是怎么做的。
So double click to open this function. So I'm going to comment this node first. So for
所以双击打开这个函数。所以我将首先对这个节点进行注释。所以对于
this node we are simply setting up severe trace star and int. And the second thing that
这个节点，我们只是简单地设置了严重的跟踪星和int。而第二件事是
I want to do, I'm going to right mouse button click and type in severe trace by object types.
我想做的第二件事是，我将按下鼠标右键，输入对象类型的严重跟踪。
And drag out this severe trace star, get it, connect it to the start, drag this one out,
拖出这个严重跟踪星，得到它，把它连接到起点，拖出这个、
connect it to int. And for the object types here, click this add button to add in word
连接到int。对于这里的对象类型，点击这个添加按钮来添加单词
static. And next thing I'm going to promote this hit location to another local variable
静态。接下来，我将把这个命中的位置提升到另一个局部变量
and click compile. Scroll down, I'm going to rename this to severe trace hit location
并点击编译。向下滚动，我将把它重命名为严重的跟踪位置
and connect this pin to here. And same as what we've done above, I'm going to copy these
并把这个引脚连接到这里。和我们上面所做的一样，我将复制这两个
two nodes and place them in here, delete this extra one and connect this pin to here. So
两个节点，并把它们放在这里，删除这个额外的节点，把这个引脚连接到这里。所以
if we want to show the debug shape and drag out this hit, use an end boolean in here, connect
如果我们想显示调试形状，并拖出这一击，在这里使用一个结束布尔值，连接
this one to here, this one to socket 8. So if we want to show the debug shape and we
这个连接到这里，这个连接到插座8。所以，如果我们想显示调试形状，并且我们
have a valid hit location, I'm going to connect this one to here. Then I'm going to use the
有一个有效的命中位置，我将把这个连接到这里。然后我将使用
function draw transform and pass in this and connect this pin to here. And the transform
函数绘制转化图，然后把这个引脚连接到这里。变形
here I'm going to click the drop down and drag out this severe trace hit location, connect
我将在这里点击下拉菜单，拖出这个严重追踪的位置，把它连接到翻译，并给它一个值。
it to translation and give it a value of three for the thickness changes mode to box. All
它与平移相连，并给它一个3的值，将厚度模式改为方框。所有的
right, I'm going to drag down this return node and I'm going to organize these nodes.
好的，我要把这个返回节点拖下来，我将组织这些节点。
So drag them to the side and I'm going to comment them. So for this nose, we are setting up severe
所以把它们拖到一边，我要对它们进行注释。所以对于这个鼻子，我们正在设置严重的
trace and next thing I'm going to add another pin, connect this C to this return node. All
追踪，接下来我要增加一个引脚，把这个C连接到这个返回节点。所有
right, click compile and I'm going to test this. So go back to my viewpro, I'm going
好的，点击编译，我要测试这个。所以回到我的viewpro，我将
to click play and we can see our debug line. I can see the hit location. Great, everything
点击播放，我们可以看到我们的调试线。我可以看到击中的位置。很好，一切
is working as usual. So this is the function that I just created. There are quite a few
都在照常工作。所以这是我刚刚创建的函数。有相当多的
nodes in it, but the function itself is not complicated at all. So feel free to refer
节点，但该函数本身一点也不复杂。所以，如果你需要帮助，可以随时参考
back to the video if you need help and I'll see you in the next lecture.
如果你需要帮助，请参考视频，我们在下一节课见。
[Music]
[音乐]